Andrew Messier

Software Engineer / Web Developer

andrewmessier.com

Charlotte, NC 28203 andrewgmessier@gmail.com (704) 743-6265 linkedin.com/in/andrewgmessier stackoverflow.com/cv/andrewmessier github.com/messman

Software engineer with four years of professional web application and toolkit development knowledge. **Experienced in building web applications,** including design/UI, UX, HTTP/AJAX, optimization, and service APIs. **Seeking new challenges in web development:** contributing to a driven team to create powerful applications that empower users and solve complex problems; assisting in business strategy and direction.

Technical Tools & Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, Babel, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS/SCSS/SASS, Node.js, ASP.NET Web API, Webpack, npm, Gulp, VS Code, .NET, Razor, Visual Studio, Docker, React, git, Visual Studio TFS, SQL

Work Experience

.NET Front End Web Developer, Jackrabbit Technologies - Huntersville, NC

August 2018 - Present

- Collaborates with Product Analysts and UX Designers to improve customer experiences.
- Communicates with Product, QA, and other developers remotely to rapidly build features in Agile Sprints.
- Assists in the modernization and organization of the codebase by working with other developers to shift the team to TypeScript.

Software Engineer, LEAD Technologies, Inc. - Charlotte, NC

June 2015 - July 2018

(Previously: Software Engineering Intern, Summers of 2013 and 2014)

- Responsible for multiple customer-facing single-page JavaScript web applications of a toolkit; optimization skills reduced load times by 50%-75%.
- Built web services for multiple platforms to bridge web applications with document processing.
- Refined HTML5 Canvas event-update-rendering patterns to significantly increase graphical responsiveness.
- Updated team's legacy code to standard builds and languages, decreasing turnaround time for bugs.

Projects

quick-tides - github.com/messman/quick-tides

2017 - Present

A mobile web app to pull NOAA data for the beach town of Wells, Maine so residents (like my parents) and their renters can have simple, fast, and reliable access to information about the weather and tides.

- Uses React for componentized UI and SCSS for organized design.
- Leverages TypeScript for compile-time type checking of props between components.
- Uses Docker and an Nginx proxy to connect the front-end application and express.js back-end data service.

simple-calc - github.com/messman/simple-calc

Late 2017

A colorful, simplistic, and responsive calculator web app that animates on keypresses.

- Used Webpack and Babel to gain experience with latest JavaScript language features and ES2015 modules.
- Used the Canvas API, requestAnimationFrame, and a bit of math to efficiently draw a complex animation.
- Saves time over default phone calculators: it always shows the calculated result and processes parentheses.

Education

University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill, NC

Class of 2015

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science – Graduation With Distinction (3.70)

- Led classes, tutored, and created assignments as an assistant for an introductory web programming course.
- Managed student-employees and assisted patrons as an on-campus recreation center building supervisor.